Okay, then let's make the score work.
And just to test it out, if we play our game and click the script over here a bunch of times, as you
can see, our score starts to increase.
Although there are a few problems that need fixing because it is clearly too big.
And if you are anything like me, you would have probably assumed we can easily change this by lowering
the set size number.
But clearly this is not the case.
But to save you the trouble of trying to figure out what is going on here, the size is actually set
by this number over here.
So what we can do is just lowering this number to say ten.
And if we hit the script you can see that it works.
Although it's still kind of appears gigantic for a second.
And this time it's because of this set size option down here.
So if we set it to a lower value like 15 and give the game another play.
So clicking on the script a bunch of times, you can see it looks much better.
Although when we pass the number ten, our numbers appear too close together.
Now, sometimes the best way to fix a problem like this is just keep changing numbers until it works.
It's the brute force method.
But to speed the time, in this case, the number we need to change is the one here, and we can change
this number to 0.4.
So giving that another go when we reach ten as you can see that looks better.
So play around with these numbers over here to get a more dramatic or less dramatic effect.
Basically whatever you think looks best.
But I'll leave it like that for now.
So now that we have the score working well and looking nice, let's implement it into our game.
And in our previous games we would just have it wait a certain amount of time and then increase the
score.
But I want something more interesting than that.
What I want is for each time we pass a tree obstacle for the score to increase.
So as you know, if we play the game and click the script, the score counts up.
And as you can see, this is a broadcast message.
So all we need to do is broadcast player score and it should go up.
So moving over to our tree sprite, all we need to do is go over to this broadcast message code and
drag it into this script here, just right before we delete the clone.
Then we can just change it so that it broadcasts the message player score.
And let's give that a go.
And as you can see, each time we pass a tree sprite, our score goes up.
It has a nice little animation.
It's almost too easy.
And look how much it transforms a game.
But one thing you may have noticed if you tried to beat the game, and that is it's still quite easy.
You can pretty much go on endlessly.
Right?
Let's fix that.
Moving over to our variable sprite, you will see that we have this disgraceful code over here.
As you should know, this isn't good code as we repeat ourselves.
So let's get rid of all this code and do something better.
Moving over to the variables group, we can create a new variable called level.
Now we can use this to control the difficulty of our game.
So grabbing a when start a forever and and if.
Here's what we're going to do.
Firstly at the start of our script we're going to set our level variable to one.
Then we're going to grab a less than operator and our level variable and stick it in here.
So basically what we want to do is check that the level is less than ten, as we don't want our game
to be too hard.
So level ten will be max.
Then we can grab a weight, stick it in here and set it to 15.
So every 15 seconds we want our level to increase by one.
So we'll just change level by one.
Now, every 15 seconds our level will increase by one and it will stop increasing when it reaches ten.
The only problem is, well, this doesn't really do anything because it's our spawn speed and speed
that change our difficulty.
So to increase the actual difficulty of the game, I'm going to use the broadcast function.
So moving over we can drag this in and then click New Message.
I'll call this one Level Up so we can now drag the when I receive block and change it to Level Up.
And then what we want to do is lower the spawn speed.
So we can drag a change variable block, set it to spawn rate and set it to -0.1.
So quickly looking at our code every 15 seconds, our game levels up which broadcasts this message which
increases our spawn speed.
So we could get an idea of the levels.
I will change this to just one second and hit play.
And as you can see that it quickly increases in difficulty until eventually we reach our max level.
And as you can see, a lot of trees spawn in.
And if this seems too hard, you can easily change it by changing this value here.
And also, let's say you wanted an insane mode where you increase the speed as well.
We could just go to our variables, drag this.
And change movement speed by minus one and giving that another go.
As you can see, our game definitely gets insane.
But anyways, I'll leave it to you to fiddle around to get it perfect because our game, rather our
masterpiece, is almost done.